Douglas Ritchie

13311 Cepeda Circle San Antonio, Texas 78023

Email: dritchie3@sbcglobal.net cell: (210)807-0331

SUMMARY:

Entrepreneur with broad managerial and technology experience; including the planning and design of new businesses and the completion of large and complex projects. Recognized for understanding and incorporating a strong understanding of business models and initiatives, industry best practices and delivering high quality results. Capable of working autonomously or collaborating with a team. Energetic, engaged, and highly motivated. Interested in a position that involves all aspects of technology, leadership and strategy development, closely linked with business operations.

STRENGTHS:

- Familiarity with Agile Project Management Methodology
- Building Technology Solutions
- Resilience and Action Planning
- Strategic Planning, Creativity, and Problem Solving
- Developing and Maintaining Cross-Business Relationships
- Staffing and Performance Management
- Navigating Complexity and Ambiguity
- Organizational Planning and Development
- Program and Project Design and Coordination
- Financial Management
- Vendor Management
- Conducting Needs Assessments and Consulting

EXPERIENCE:

DBRI Properties CEO and Owner 1998 - Current

- Oversight of a multi-state portfolio of properties.
- Maintain property management company and vendor relationships.
- Direct finance and maintenance decisions.
- Ensure a positive renter experience.

SWIM READY Sole Proprietor 2013 – 2018

- Designed the concept and built the brand.
- Established and maintained a robust book of business.
- Liaison to customers.
- Problem solved complex customer concerns.
- Establish and maintain vendor relationships.

GLASS DOCTOR Franchise Owner 2010 - 2012

- Partnered with franchise consultant to establish the business, including location, brand, and resources.
- Hired and coached employees.
- Responsible for employee relations and performance management.
- Financial and Legal oversight.
- Established customer base and liaison for large customer contracts.
- Trained, coached and partnered with coordinator on scheduling, customer relations and employee relations.

Managed vendor relationships.

R&S COMPUTERS President and Co-Owner 1997 – 2001

- Provided materials and consulting for computer shipping companies worldwide.
- Managed and trained employees on the intake and fulfillment of orders.
- Developed vendor partnerships to sourced parts and materials.
- Configured systems, imaged computers, and handled accessories through drop ship,
- Troubleshoot and problem solve customer technology concerns and questions.

AGLA (American General Life and Accident Insurance Company) Sales Agent 1992 - 1997

- Consultant to clients regarding life and accident insurance options.
- Sourced, established and serviced a book of clients.

Sears Sales Associate
Integrated Networks Circuit Assembly

EDUCATION:

California State University, Long Beach

Bachelor of Arts Degree in Communications

Currently enrolled in UTSA Software Development Boot-camp Microsoft Certified Service Engineer